{
    "id": "41cd7f84e6e64cf294b1f9a4c845de1f",
    "title": "Mixed Conditionals",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Unless you ……………………… drinking, you will develop serious health problems.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "stop",
                "stopped",
                "had stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e377e1c021de4073b8ec4ebb78d810b5"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. I tried harder, I could have won.",
            "description": "Had I tried harder means the same as ‘if I had tried harder’. This sentence is in the third conditional.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Had",
                "Should"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "18c6d40f870445a3b3e7ac3d9329525b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Provided that you ……………………… now, you will be able to reach there before sunset.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "started",
                "had started"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "04441f41a2a747b1aef4ad1e026cd950"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………….. you, I should get that car serviced.",
            "description": "The structure if I were you is used to give advice.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "76a4ab59e6c64214be52431569dbb053"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I …………………………… worry.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "won't",
                "wouldn't",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7bcad1b1c91b4be795db33a61ee14413"
        },
        {
            "question": "Had I realized what you intended, I ………………………….. to come with you.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "wouldn't agree",
                "wouldn't have agreed",
                "won't agree"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "34ca3d7733f6414998cb87a1875bad55"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will get up earlier if there ……………………… a good reason to.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b6926b9ba124467ba4175b0e46bb8e30"
        },
        {
            "question": "It would be nice if you …………………………… me with the housework.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "help",
                "helped",
                "had helped"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "00ec2573495340baaefdc6183ed90fc3"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………….. you free, we could go out for a meal.",
            "description": "'Were you free' means the same as ‘if you were free’.",
            "answers": [
                "Should",
                "Were",
                "Had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8eceb2cb32964cd0a174600fb45809b4"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………… early, give me a ring.",
            "description": "'If you should finish' means more or less the same as 'if you finish'.",
            "answers": [
                "finish",
                "should finish",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a8d3da7f3cda44969ea3d8883c46f930"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………….. meet James, perhaps you could tell him the news.",
            "description": "If you should meet James means the same as If you happen to meet James.",
            "answers": [
                "happen to",
                "should",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b80baf8825ed40469759ae8dcadc1697"
        },
        {
            "question": "How would we cope if I …………………………. to lose my job?",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "02af8a66a5ea4176af03d42f15f177a6"
        }
    ]
}